Jerome Thayananthajothy

+44-7498-373069 · tjthavarshan@gmail.com · thavarshan.xyz 41 Fitz Roy Avenue, Harborne, Birmingham, B17 8RL

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Engineering professional and collaborator with 5+ years of experience devoted to Software Development, 2+ as a Team Lead. In-depth knowledge of SQL and NoSQL databases, PHP, TypeScript and related frameworks, AWS, Docker, licensing with external partners and approval standards. Proficient at multitasking and management of large 10+ or small 4 person teams with a proven track record for being highly efficient at developing budget sensitive product using group brainstorming, innovation, graphics, and materials that tell a story and resonates with consumers in varied account types and retail experiences.

SKILLS

Expert in

PHP, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Laravel, Symfony, VueJS, NodeJS

Intermediate in

Machine Learning, C++, Java, MongoDB, ReactJS, NestJS, ExpressJS, Flask

Basic in

Rust, DynamoDB

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MacroActive Ltd, Colombo

Jun 2021 - Nov 2022

- **Senior Software Engineer**
 - Worked extensively with PHP, TypeScript, VueJS, ReactJS AWS Dynamo DB and MongoDB.
 - · Designed, developed and deployed three major projects and was working on fourth project before resignation.
 - Responsibilities included but was not limited to training new recruits, performing code reviews and planning weekly sprints.

Elegant Media, Colombo Software Engineer

Apr 2019 - Jul 2020

- Designed, developed and deployed numerous Laravel projects.
- Performed code reviews and was one of the biggest contributors to the internal projects and systems of the company.

Seven's Idea, Colombo

Jan 2018 - Mar 2019

Software Engineer

- Designed, developed and deployed numerous WordPress and Laravel projects including the main IT infrastructure of the company.
- Performed numerous marketing and branding design requirements

Alta Vision Solar Ltd, Colombo

Jun 2015 - Jan 2018

Software Engineer

- Responsible for all marketing material for the company and for all client projects received.
- Designed, developed, tested and deployed multiple Laravel projects and WordPress websites.
- In charge of the Graphic design projects.

Sri Lanka Telecom, Trincomalee

Oct 2016 - Dec 2016

Telecom Engineering Intern

- Mentored by the industries finest Telecom Engineers including the regional manager himself.
- Learned all the soft skills necessary for any trade.

Sri Lanka Telecom, Trincomalee

Oct 2015 - Jan 2016

Telecom Engineering Intern

• Provided with basic training required for a career in Telecommunications Engineering.

EDUCATION

Institution of Engineers Sri Lanka College of Engineering

Graduate Diploma in Electronics & Telecommunications Engineering

University of Sunderland

Bachelor of Science (Honors) Computer Systems Engineering

International College of Business and Technology

Higher National Diploma in Software Engineering